<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>golang on Lorenzo Peppoloni</title>
    <link>/tags/golang/</link>
    <description>Recent content in golang on Lorenzo Peppoloni</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 07:13:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/golang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Is GO good at Math?</title>
      <link>/posts/gomath/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 07:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/gomath/</guid>
      <description>We don&#39;t usually associate GO with a language to do mathematics, geometry or deep learning. Those tasks are usually left mainly to Python.
But is GO good at math as well?
Disclaimer
This post is an effort to share my experience and knowledge about the topic. Are there languages that are a better fit for math? Yes. Is it possible to do math (at least some simple things) with GO? Yes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All you need to know about Learning Tests</title>
      <link>/posts/learningtests/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 07:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/learningtests/</guid>
      <description>Picture this scenario: You have to solve a new task, a new amazing coding problem, after some googling, you find a library that solve part of the problem for you. Great! You write your code using the library, you write a test&amp;hellip;and
FAIL!
You tweak the code a bit&amp;hellip;FAIL!
I think we all went through this multiple times during our developer career.
What is happening is that, you found a new library to implement a certain behaviour that you want, you think you understood the library (but you have this bugging feeling that maybe you did not), you think you know how to use it for your particular use case (but you have this bugging feeling that maybe you do not).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Table-driven tests in Python</title>
      <link>/posts/tabledriventestspy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tabledriventestspy/</guid>
      <description>Table-driven tests are an elegant and functional way to unittest your functions in Go. Let&amp;rsquo;s see some ideas on how to introduce this same testing pattern in Python.
What are table-driven tests One thing I really love about Go is table-driven tests. If you are not familiar with them, table-driven tests are a very elegant way to write unittests for your code. The basic idea is that you write a list of named test cases, defining the input and the expected output for each test case, then you loop over the cases, run your function and check that the actual output is equal to the expected one.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>